Guide to the Chester Ittner Bliss Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Council symposium material, 1953-1956 (Box 25)
- Miscellaneous bulletins, 1953-1956 (Box 25)
- Membership lists/directories of various professional societies, 1963-1976; 4 (Box 25)
- Notebook of tables, 1947-1954 (Box 26)
- Chapter 27, 1934-1952 (Box 26)
- Chapter 25, 1947-1948 (Box 26)
- Chapter 21 (binder reads 24), 1957 (Box 26)
- Collaborative assay of USP standard insulin, 1944 (Box 26)
- Chapter 23, 1952 (Box 26)
- USP insulin advisory board, 1950-1954 (Box 26)
- USP Corticotropin (ACTH) assay study panel, 1951 (Box 26)
- Notebook (not labeled), 1952 (Box 26)
- Lecture by J.W. Tukey, 1950 (Box 26)
- Report #5, Agriculture Experiment Station, Iowa, 1950 (Box 26)
- Statistical Tables for Biological Agricultural and Medical Research, 1963 (Box 26)
- Chapter 18, Statistics in Biology Vol. II, Undated; 2 (Box 27)
- Chapter 19, Undated (Box 27)
- Chapter 17, Undated (Box 27)
- Notebooks (not labeled), Undated; 2 (Box 27)
- Class/Lecture notes, Undated; 2 (Box 27)
- Syllabus and exercises, Undated (Box 27)
- Chapter 14-20 (printed) of Statistics in Biology, Vol. II in 3 ring binders, Undated; 4 (Box 27)
- Vitamin D chick assay, AVRC collaborative study: original data, 1944 (Box 28)
- Anti-thyroid tests data from McGinty and Bywater, 1944-1945 (Box 28)
- Report and original data from USP penicillin assay, 1944 (Box 28)
- Bioassay of adrenal cortex extract, correspondence with Pabst, original data, 1948-1953 (Box 28)
- Biological assay, Bliss and Cattell, references and calculations, 1936-1941 (Box 28)
- Original data on USP reference standard in cats, 1942-1946 (Box 28)
- Heart measurements of growing boys and girls, Meresh data and analysis, 1950-1951 (Box 28)
- Meprobamate bibliography (unabridged), 1958 (Box 28)
- Notes from a Laboratory of Medical Statistics, 1964-1965; 2 (Box 28)
- Notes from a Laboratory of Medical Statistics, 1959-1964; 3 (Box 29)
- Donald Mainland notes on medical statistics, 1966-1970; 3 (Box 29)
- Outline of biometry mimeo handouts, 1941-1953; 3 (Box 29)
- Tentative contents for An Outline of Biometry Diary, 1941 (Box 29)
- Statistics in Biology, Vol. II - Chapters 14-16, 20, Undated; 4 (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous date, 1941-1969; 2 (Box 30)
- Notebook (not labeled), 1947 (Box 30)
- Lecture notes, 1961 (Box 30)
- Appreciation of R.A. Fisher, 1962-1963 (Box 30)
- Chapter 27, Undated (Box 30)
- Reprint by Bliss, Undated (Box 30)
- Data and notes for Vol. III of Statistics in Biology, 1947 (Box 30)
- Chapter 25, Undated (Box 30)
- Miscellaneous papers from desk, 1977-1998 (Box 30)
- Kraemer Bulletin --- Static Bending Tests, 1948 (Box 30)
- Sampling surveys, 1952-1953 (Box 31)
- Logarithmic distribution, 1939-1963 (Box 31)
- Complex contingency tables, 1958-1959 (Box 31)
- Extensions of the bionomial, 1952-1956 (Box 31)
- Balanced incomplete blocks, 1936-1937 (Box 31)
- Preference tests, 1949-1953 (Box 31)
- Partial correlation, 1950-1955 (Box 31)
- Numerical examples - drug assays, 1946-1970 (Box 31)
- Chapter 21: Stan Bergman copy, 1946-1951 (Box 31)
- Complex designs, 1943-1965 (Box 31)
- Functional relations, 1946-1953 (Box 31)
- Discriminants for assays, 1955-1965 (Box 31)
- Unequal sub-class numbers, 1955-1965 (Box 31)
- Pea aphids, 1942-1943 (Box 31)
- Bean beetle - Tuner, 1942-1946 (Box 31)
- Grape berry moth-Still, 1938-1954 (Box 31)
- Collaborative analgesic experiments, 1947 (Box 31)
- Finances, 1961 (Box 32)
- Chapter 7, Undated (Box 32)
- Income tax-old, 1938-1949 (Box 32)
- Income tax - old, 1951-1955 (Box 32)
- Income tax - old, 1949 (Box 32)
- Class in biometry, 1943-1961; 18 (Box 32)
- Yale Class, 1962-1965; 3 (Box 32)
- Letters received and sent to Bliss while in Europe Sabbatical year, 1953-1961 (Box 32)
- Gause visit, 1959-1960 (Box 32)
- Visit to Russia, 1960-1961 (Box 32)
- Arrangements for world trip, 1961 (Box 32)
- Outline of biometry, 1954 (Box 32)
- R.A. Fisher memorial, 1962-1966 (Box 32)
- Conferences in Canada, ISI Discrete symposium, 1963 (Box 32)
- Contrasts, 1961-1962 (Box 32)
- Correspondence, 1951 (Box 32)
- Statistical seminars, 1951 (Box 32)
- American Heart Journal, 1954-1958 (Box 32)
- Correspondence with Kit, 1961-1962 (Box 32)
- Fisher obituaries, bibliographies, etc, 1954-1963 (Box 32)
- ENAR, 1955-1958 (Box 32)
- Sub-committee on biology of the committee on applied mathematical statistics, NRC, 1946-1954 (Box 32)
- War gas research, 1943-1945 (Box 32)
- Reference tables, 1943-1951 (Box 32)
- Nomograph of obtaining logit 1, 1944 (Box 32)
- Table II: corrected and expected probits, 1941 (Box 32)
- Finances, 1972-1978 (Box 33)
- Validating the anova, 1955 (Box 33)
- Yale Class biometry 157, 1965-1968 (Box 33)
- Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 33)
- AAAS, 1971 (Box 33)
- Biometric society, 1967-1976 (Box 33)
- Statistical lab - Yale, 1962-1968 (Box 33)
- McGraw-Hill marketing, 1965-1977 (Box 33)
- Letters and accounts, McGraw-Hill book, 1965-1973 (Box 33)
- Paul DesRoche, 1974-1975 (Box 33)
- Correspondence, 1966-1978 (Box 33)
- Reprints for binding, Undated (Box 33)
- Masters rectangular hyperbola, Undated (Box 33)
- Chapter 21 - bioassays from Parallel regressions, 1956-1966 (Box 33)
- Outline of book: other projects, Undated (Box 33)
- Other insect counts, Undated (Box 33)
- Parallel-line bioassays, 1953-1966 (Box 33)
- Penicillin assays MSS, 1944-1946 (Box 33)
- Bioassays examples, 1941-1958 (Box 33)
- Bioassays exercises, 1941-1958 (Box 33)
- Bioassays with convariance, 1938-1963 (Box 33)
- Slope-ratio assays, 1951-1956 (Box 33)
- Convergent slopes-examples, 1952-1959 (Box 34)
- Comparison of slopes, 1951-1956 (Box 34)
- Associated measurments, 1960-1962 (Box 34)
- Bivariate distributions, 1946-1958 (Box 34)
- Two distributions of counts, 1964-1969 (Box 34)
- Poisson distributions, 1940-1970 (Box 34)
- Negative binomials, 1943-1968 (Box 34)
- Incomplete distributions, 1938-1967 (Box 34)
- Negative binomials with a common K, 1942-1955 (Box 34)
- Discrete log-normal, 1948-1963 (Box 34)
- Overdispersed distributions, 1948-1970 (Box 34)
- Other count distributions, 1959-1970 (Box 34)
- Comparison of counts, 1942-1970 (Box 34)
- Chapter 27 incomplete, 1939-1951 (Box 34)
- The significance of a difference, 1950 (Box 34)
- Angular transformation, 1938-1968; 3 (Box 34)
- Square-root transformation, 1936-1970 (Box 34)
- Logarithmic transformation, 1938-1963 (Box 34)
- Discriminants with counts, 1959-1961 (Box 34)
- Regressions from counts, 1943-1955 (Box 34)
- Human assay of digitalis, 1942-1959 (Box 34)
- Dosage-mortality curves for insects, 1933-1941 (Box 34)
- All-or-none bioassays, 1948-1961 (Box 34)
- Probit curves, 1943-1965 (Box 35)
- Regression with entomological data, linear and partial, 1919-1937 (Box 35)
- Curves in angles, 1953-1955 (Box 35)
- Dosage-Mortality Curves from survivors, 1940-1943 (Box 35)
- Joint action of drugs, 1941-1966 (Box 35)
- Joint toxic action, 1934-1956 (Box 35)
- Sequential samples, 1944-1957 (Box 35)
- Masters probit analysis, 1951 (Box 35)
- Masters insect trap records, 1939 (Box 35)
- Masters periodic regression, Undated (Box 35)
- Chapter 23, Undated (Box 35)
- Chapter 27 masters, Undated (Box 35)
- Card file - A-J, Undated (Box 36A)
- Card file - K-Z, Undated (Box 36B)
- Card file - A-Z, Undated (Box 36C)
- Reprints (research for chapter 27?), Undated (Box 37)
- Papers given by others at symposia, 1976 (Box 37)
- ISI, 1971; 2 (Box 37)
- Articles and reports by others, 1973-1976 (Box 37)
- Biometric Society, 1975-1976 (Box 37)
- Reprints by others, 1943-1965 (Box 37)
- NBS, 1971 (Box 37)
- USP XII bulletins, Undated (Box 38)
- Computer print-outs, 1967 (Box 39)
- Convariance-Finney, Undated (Box 40)
- Charts, graphs on assorted topics, Undated (Box 40)
- Correspondence/greeting cards, Undated (Box 40)
- Mathematical statistics notebook, Undated (Box 40)
- Lattice squares in corn selection tests, calculations and data, 1941 (Box 40)
- Symposium notebook, 1953 (Box 40)